in a video that I uploaded last week
在我上周上传的一段视频中
discussing some of the differences
讨论其中的一些差异
between illustrator and inkscape one of
在Illustrator和Inkscape之间
the items that I pointed out was that in
我指出的项目是在
inkscape you don't have the ability to
Inkscape你没有能力
generate charts and graphs like you can
尽您所能生成图表和图表
in illustrator but it turns out I spoke
在Illustrator中，但事实证明我说了
too soon on that one as a commenter
作为评论者，对这一点的评论还为时过早
pointed out there is an extension in
指出中有一个扩展
inkscape that allows you to do this and
Inkscape允许您这样做，并且
although it is pretty rudimentary it
虽然它是相当初级的，但它
does work well enough so let's go over
确实工作得很好，所以让我们再来一遍
how to use this extension
如何使用此扩展
I'm going to open up a new document and
我要打开一份新文档，
to access this extension we're going to
要访问此扩展，我们将访问
come up here to where it says extensions
到上面写着分机的地方来
we're going to go down to render
我们要下去渲染一下
and the item we're looking for is nice
而且我们要找的东西很好
charts
海图
and in this menu
在这个菜单中
if you come over here to where it says
如果你到这里来，上面写着
data you can see we have two different
您可以看到，我们有两个不同的数据
types of data that we can input we can
我们可以输入的数据类型
choose data from a file I haven't tried
从我没有尝试过的文件中选择数据
this myself but apparently you can
这是我自己的，但显然你可以
import data from a CSV file if you'd
从CSV文件导入数据(如果您
like and then over here we have direct
像这样，然后在这里我们有直接的
input which is we're going to be
输入，即我们将成为
focusing on for this lesson
本课的重点是
now this is where things get a little
现在是事情变得有点复杂的地方
complicated if you come down here to
很复杂，如果你来这里
this text input box you'll see this is
您将看到的文本输入框如下所示
how we go about adding items to our
我们如何将物品添加到我们的
chart so every item that you add has to
图表，因此您添加的每个项目都必须
have a name here like I've done I've
在这里有一个名字，就像我曾经做过的那样
written in Sample item and then add a
在样例项中编写，然后添加一个
colon and then the number representing
冒号，然后是表示
the percentage of that chart and then
该图表的百分比，然后
add a comma separating it from the next
加一个逗号将它与下一个分开
item
项目
so it's kind of like writing code here
所以这有点像是在这里写代码
you're gonna have to write this for each
你得为每个人写下这个
one of the items that you want in your
您希望在您的
chart and if you're using the percentage
图表，如果使用的是百分比
pie chart like I'm using you're going to
像我用的饼状图一样你要
want to make sure that these numbers add
我想确保这些数字相加
up to 100.
最多100个。
so I'm going to move this menu off to
所以我要把这份菜单移到
the side and I'm going to tick the live
一边，我要在现场打勾
preview box
预览框
and it's going to show you a preview of
它将向您展示一个预览
what gets generated here
在此生成的内容
so if I come down here to the chart type
因此，如果我在这里介绍图表类型
drop down you can see we have four
下拉你可以看到我们有四个
different types of charts that we can
不同类型的图表，我们可以
choose from if I choose bar chart
如果我选择条形图，则从中选择
we get something like this right here if
我们这里有类似的东西，如果
I choose pie chart we get the regular
我选择饼图，我们得到常规的
pie chart
饼图
if we choose pie chart percentage it
如果我们选择饼图百分比
gives you the same pie chart but with
为您提供相同的饼图，但带有
the numbers having a percentage symbol
有百分比符号的数字
after them
在他们之后
and then finally we have stacked bar
然后我们终于有了堆叠的酒吧
chart down here which looks like that
下面的图表看起来是这样的
so I'm going to go back to pie chart
所以我要回到饼图
percentage
百分比
and if you come over here to the labels
如果你到这里来看看唱片公司
tab we have some options that we can
标签我们有一些选项，我们可以
work with you can change the font if
使用您可以在以下情况下更改字体
you'd like you can change the font size
您希望您可以更改字体大小
and you could change the font color now
您现在可以更改字体颜色
the problem with using this menu is that
使用此菜单的问题是
if you want to change the color you're
如果你想改变颜色，你可以
going to have to manually type in the
将不得不手动键入
hex code and if you want to change the
十六进制代码，如果要更改
font you'll have to manually type in the
FONT您必须手动键入
font name here so maybe this menu isn't
字体名称在此处，因此此菜单可能不是
the best way to go about doing this once
做一次这件事的最好方法是
you're finished generating the chart you
您已经完成了图表的生成
can go and do all of that retroactively
可以追溯地去做所有的事情
using the text tool in the fill and
使用填充中的文本工具和
stroke menu so that's probably a much
中风菜单，所以这可能是一个很多
easier way to do that so I'm going to
更简单的方法，所以我要
ignore this part of the menu and I'll
忽略菜单的这一部分，我将
come over here to the charts tab
请到这里的图表选项卡
and if you notice we have some more
如果你注意到我们有更多的
options that we can work with more
我们可以使用更多选项
specifically we have the color scheme
具体来说，我们有配色方案
that we can change if I click on this
如果我点击这个，我们就可以改变
drop down right here I can choose a blue
在这里下拉，我可以选择蓝色的
color scheme which looks like that I can
看起来像这样的配色方案我可以
choose gray which looks like that
选择看起来像那样的灰色
and then we have contrast and then we
然后我们有对比，然后我们
have sap
有汁液
so that's what those options look like
所以这就是那些选项的样子
I'm going to set this back to default
我要将其设置为默认设置
again this would probably be easier to
再说一次，这可能会更容易
change after we generate the chart so
在我们生成图表后更改，因此
I'm going to leave that as it is for now
我现在就不说了
and then over here we can add or remove
然后在这里我们可以添加或删除
a drop shadow so this is what it looks
一个阴影，所以这是它看起来的样子
like with the drop shadow added beneath
就像在下面添加了投影
the chart if I deselect that we just
如果我取消选中该图表，我们只需
have a flat chart as you can see there
有一张你可以在那里看到的平面图
and then finally I'll come over here to
最后我会到这里来
the values tab now the values represent
现在，值选项卡中的值表示
the numbers after the item name so if
物品名称后的数字，因此如果
you don't want those numbers being
你不会想让这些数字
displayed there you can just untick that
显示在那里，您只需取消勾选
box and then those values will be
框中，则这些值将是
removed
移除
so I'm going to put them back on there
所以我要把它们放回去
and once you're finished you can just
一旦你完成了，你就可以
click the apply button and then close
单击应用按钮，然后关闭
out of the menu and now you have a pie
从菜单上拿出来，现在你有一个馅饼
chart that you can work with and you can
您可以使用的图表，您可以
click on these items individually and
逐个点击这些项目，然后
change their colors like any other
像任何其他颜色一样改变它们的颜色
Vector object as you see me doing here
向量对象，就像您在这里看到的那样
and if you want to change the font of
如果您要更改的字体
the text you just grab your text tool
文本你只需要抓取你的文本工具
um if you could find it I'm just going
嗯，如果你能找到的话我要走了
to press the letter t on the keyboard to
按键盘上的字母t以
access it and you can just triple click
访问它，您只需点击三次即可
your text to select it and choose a new
您的文本以选择它并选择一个新的
font using the text menu if you'd like
如果您愿意，可以使用文本菜单
so that's how you can go about
所以这就是你可以走的路
generating charts and graphs using the
使用生成图表和图形
nice charts extension in inkscape
Inkscape中的精美图表扩展
if you found this lesson useful then
如果你觉得这一课很有用，那么
consider checking out my inkscape master
考虑一下我的Inkscape大师
class it's a collection of over 60
班级它是一个超过60个人的集合
videos where I go over all of the tools
我浏览了所有工具的视频
and features in inkscape and I explain
和Inkscape中的功能，我解释
what they are and demonstrate how they
它们是什么并演示它们如何
work kind of like how I did in this
就像我在这件事上做的那样
video we even have a private Community
视频我们甚至有一个私人社区
where you can ask questions and get help
在这里您可以提出问题并获得帮助
from me anytime you want and best of all
在你想要的任何时候从我这里，最好的是
there's no monthly membership fees you
你不需要缴纳月费
just pay 17 one time and you're in for
只需一次性支付17英镑，你就会面临
Life I'll have some information about
我会有一些关于生活的信息
that down below if you want to check
如果您想查看下面的内容
that out as always thanks for watching
这是一如既往的感谢收看
all right
好的